<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: oscp | Bob1Bob2]]></title>
  <link href="http://wg135.github.io/blog/categories/oscp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wg135.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-25T09:21:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://wg135.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bob1Bob2]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[about OSCP]]></title>
    <link href="http://wg135.github.io/blog/2017/01/25/thoughts-about-oscp/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-25T13:37:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://wg135.github.io/blog/2017/01/25/thoughts-about-oscp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Haven&rsquo;t update my notes for about 90-120 days. I spent last 3 month in OSCP lab and finally got my first milestone on my way to slag dragon.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>EXAM:</h2>

<h3>Exam round 1:</h3>

<p>Battle plan: start at 4:00PM. Knock out 4 machines</p>

<p>The exam connection package came at 4:00PM. I started my first machine and got root at 6:00PM. Then I started on an easy box and got the root at 7:00 PM. I felt I was on roll and I thought man that’s easy. Then I had a quick dinner and jumped to third machine without rest (this was a mistake).</p>

<p>Bad thing happened, until 2:00AM, I focused on 2 machines. I made no progress. I decided to go to bed and felt so frustrated and pain. At that time, I changed my battle plan that only focus on the last machine, since if I could root that box, I may have 60 points in the exam and another 10 points in the lab, so I may still have chance to pass.</p>

<p>Next day 7:00AM. I started work on last box. 10:00AM, got shell, I felt I see the light in the tunnel. Started to do privilege escalation. Until 3:00PM no progress. Finally, I found the vulnerability at last moment but VPN time out.</p>

<p>After one day got the result:</p>

<h2>failed</h2>

<p>After the exam, I didn’t extend lab. I created many VMs for practice. Many windows and Linux local privilege exploits code are compiled. I went back to vulnhub and downloaded many VMs to practice and wait for round two.</p>

<h3>Exam round 2:</h3>

<p>Battle plan: start at 8:00AM. Knock out 4 machines</p>

<p>Got first root at 9:00AM. At 9:30AM got another one. So in first 90 mins, I got 2 machines. But I was not excited. I knew hard part was not coming yet. Until 5:00PM, I got a limited shell in a box. I started to do privilege exploit on it but until 9:00PM, I made no progress. Started to feel frustrated. I took one hour break then decided to try another machine. 11:00 PM got limited shell. 1:00 AM got root. I was really tired at that time; I took another 1-hour break. 2:00AM I started my last ditch. I tried to get the root in the machine I got shell and tried to get limited shell on the last box. I found a vulnerability on the last box, but I didn’t successfully trigger it. VPN time out again.</p>

<p>The time I got 3 roots and 1 shell. I guess I got 65 points in the exam and there are 10 lab report points may be added.</p>

<p>After one day got the result:</p>

<h2>pass!</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
